In this lesson, we're going to talk about how to identify problems.
When you're building products,
one of the most important things is to make sure that you are solving the right problems.
PM spend a lot of time just doing that.
They understand the market, the user,
business goals, and then identify opportunities.
There really is no shortage of problems that could be solved,
but one of the hardest things to do is to decide what not to solve.
In this lesson, we'll cover the following topics;
identifying opportunities, understanding the market,
the target user, what total addressable market is,
creating and evaluating hypotheses,
and building a business case.
All right, let's get going.