So now let's walk through the calculation that I did.
There's 330 million people in the United States,
and I'm assuming that streaming services is something that
most people will be interested in or you use at some point.
Similar to how traditional television has penetrated the market.
Most streaming services costs around $10 or so a month.
So that's the number I'm going to be using.
So if we take 330 million people and we
multiply it by $10 per month and 12 months in a year,
we end up with a TAM of $39.6 billion.
So let's refine this a little bit though.
Streaming services are generally sold and shared within a household,
not to individual people,
similar to how a cable TV subscription would work.
So there's roughly a 130 million households in the US.
The $10 per month price point will stay the same.
But if we update the equation to use
a 130 million households at $10 per month and 12 months in a year,
we end up with a TAM of $15.6 billion.
How did these numbers compared to the ones that you calculated?
Were they higher or lower?
Or maybe even the same.