Now we're going to talk a little bit about testing a hypothesis.
You can test and evaluate your hypothesis in several different ways.
You can do this through user interviews,
where you go and talk to your users,
walk them through your thinking,
and get their thoughts and feedback.
This works best when you have a prototype
that you can show to users and ask them to evaluate.
It's also helpful to get a sense if this is something that they
would use and if it's something that they would consider buying,
why and why not.
This will help you to understand if you're solving a problem for users,
as well as how users are perceiving your solution.
You also can get feedback from focus groups.
You'll get a group of users together in a room at
the same time and then you'll have a conversation with all of them.
It's a little bit different than one on one interviews,
because participants in a focus group will interact with each other.
They'll build on top of each others ideas or disagree and provide alternative views.
One thing to watch out for here though, is group thinking.
This is where there's only one opinion that surfaces within the group.
You can also run surveys for some of the higher level questions you might have.
Surveys are great when you want to get feedback from lots of people.
But, you are a little bit more limited in the types
of questions that you can ask and how deep you can go.
Think of having multiple choice versus being
able to have an in depth conversation about a topic.
You'll get some insight,
but it won't be as detailed as what you would get from an interview.
For all three of these options,
it'll be super helpful to work with a researcher who can help you
to set this up and structure it in a way that will minimize bias.
You can also put your hypotheses into a design sprint.
This will help to stress test the way
the problem is framed and further define a solution.
The last phase of the design sprint is validate,
where you'll put concepts in front of real users and get their feedback.
We'll talk more about what exactly happens in a design sprint in the next course.
As you're going through this process,
if you find that you're not addressing a customer need or your solution isn't providing
value or your product isn't differentiated enough or there's no willingness to pay,
stop, it's not worth pursuing this.
You don't have product market fit.
You should go back and tweak which customer you're focusing
on or your solution or your pricing model.
But at the end of the day,
you want to make sure that you believe in your hypotheses and that you
have the data to back them up before you start building a product.