Understanding the market is critical to building successful products.
Some markets are better than others and some products do a better job than others.
You'll want to find product/market fit.
So what exactly is product/market fit?
Well, product/market fit means being in
a good market with a product that can satisfy that market.
The next thing that you might be asking yourself is what makes a good market?
Let's talk through a few things that go into this.
The first is size.
The more people or the more need,
the more adoption and the easier it will be to monetize your product.
The next factor is growth.
Is the market growing?
Think about how many people have smartphones today compared to 20 years ago.
Lastly is acquisition.
How easy is it to get new customers?
Think about expanding your reach and your ability to explain your product to new users.
This can also include getting people to switch from competing products.
Think about how much friction there is between
switching from an Android phone to an iOS phone,
or from changing your e-mail provider from one to another.
It can be a little bit tricky to identify product/market fit,
but here are a few signs that you don't have good product/market fit.
First of all, if users aren't getting value from your product,
this will cause a whole bunch of other problems.
For example, as a result,
they won't recommend it or talk about your product with other people.
This also means that there's no excitement about your product.
The press doesn't really care,
or maybe the articles that are written about your product are boring and bland.
Lastly, all of this will lead to very slow growth and make it difficult
for you to sell your product because you are not providing any value for the user.
On the other side,
here are a few signs when you can tell that you've found good product/market fit.
It all starts with users getting a ton of value from using your product.
It's solving a super important need for them.
The product as a result,
will practically sell itself.
Users will recommend it to others,
and it's easy to immediately understand the value and why someone would want it.
The press is also super excited,
and they're banging on your door to talk to you about your product and learn more.
Lastly, because your product is in such high demand,
it can sometimes be difficult to keep up.
For example, maybe you are constantly
needing to add more servers in order to support your app.
So how can you get more insight into markets?
Well, there's lots of ways to do that.
It's important to familiarize yourself as much as
possible with what's going on around your product space.
This can be done by doing online research to better understand what's happening in
the market by staying up-to-date on
news that might be relevant to the problem that you're focused on.
You can also look at similar products in
the space and see how they've approached the problem,
and what's working well and maybe where they're struggling.
Trends can also provide very important insights.
One of the most helpful is Mary Meeker's Annual Internet Trends Report.
I read this every single year and there's tons and tons of interesting information.
I'll include a link to this report in the classroom.
Google Trends can also be a helpful tool to get a sense of
what people are searching for and how that is changing over time.
So now that you have an understanding of markets and
how to get insights about them, let's try it out.