For this exercise, imagine that the team is interested in building
a product to help people better track their fitness and improve their health over time.
Spend a little bit of time doing some research to better
understand current trends and the fitness tracking market.
Here's some questions to get you started.
What benefits does improving fitness provide?
What products are already in the market?
How much money and time do people spend on health and fitness?
What are some of the different ways to deliver fitness tracking,
and what are the pros and cons of those approaches?
Now spend a little bit of time answering
these questions and anything else that comes to mind,
and then check out my solution in the next video.