So I did a little bit of research for industry trends for fitness tracking,
and here's what I came up with.
According to Mayo Clinic,
there are a handful of benefits of regular physical activity.
Exercise can help you to control your weight,
whether you have a goal related to lose,
maintain, or gain weight.
Regular exercise can also help to prevent or manage many different types of conditions,
including stroke, high blood pressure,
and depression, and anxiety.
Physical activity can cause endorphins to be released,
which can leave you feeling happier and more relaxed.
Physical exercise also helps to boost your self confidence.
Regular physical activity can build
your endurance and it helps your cardiovascular system work more efficiently,
which in turn helps you to have more energy.
Lastly, regular exercise can help you sleep better.
This includes both falling asleep faster as well as having a higher quality of sleep.
So what fitness and health tracking products already exist?
Well, there's a handful of smartwatches out there that also include
fitness features like the Apple watch and many Android watches.
They also include a lot of other features and functionalities as well.
Then there's also a handful of smart watches that are much more fitness focus,
like the Fitbit and the Galaxy Fit.
There's also a handful of fitness related apps.
Similar to watches, there are more general fitness apps that do
a lot of things like Apple Activity and Health apps and Google Fit,
and then there's apps that are more focused on
specific activities like Nike Running Club, RunKeeper, and Freeletics.
One other product that I came across while I was doing research,
that I thought was interesting,
is a product called the Motiv Ring.
It's a ring that you wear on your finger and it tracks
your heart rate activity and sleep patterns 24 hours a day,
seven days a week, and it starts at $200.
So how much do people spend on health and fitness?
Well, a company called Myprotein,
surveyed 1,350 adults in the US to age 18 to 65,
and found that the average American spends $155 per month or $1,860 per year.
When you break this down,
they found that people on average spend $56 a month on health supplements,
$35 a month on clothing and accessories,
$33 a month on gym memberships,
$17 a month for healthy meal plans,
and $14 a month for trainers.
So now let's look at some of
the different ways that we could potentially deliver health tracking.
One option would be to build specific hardware,
like a watch that users would wear in order to track their health.
The other option would be to create an app that users can
download on their phone to track and record their health and fitness.
But there's also an in-between where we could create
an app that could run on an existing watch in order to track fitness.
So let's look at the pros and cons of these three different methods.
There were three different things that I wanted to
look at when thinking through pros and cons.
The first was investment.
How much effort will it require to build this product?
The second is ease of use for the user.
What will be the best experience for
the user with the least amount of effort on their part?
Lastly, market.
How big is the market if we were to enter it?
For investment, building any type of hardware is
a huge investment and requires a lot of expertise across a number of skill sets.
Building an app for a watch or a phone now isn't quite as complex.
In terms of ease of use,
how much effort does the user have to put into
use the product in order to get the most out of it?
With hardware, it's fairly effortless.
As long as the user is wearing it,
there's nothing extra that they have to do to get the product to work.
With the watch app,
there's some minor friction,
but if the users wearing the watch,
all they really need to do is open the app.
With the phone app,
there's more friction because the user has to have
their phone with them while exercising and they have to open it up.
Lastly, in terms of market,
I think that building a watch would have
the smallest market since it's already a pretty crowded space,
and smartwatches tend to be more expensive.
In terms of building an app for a watch,
it's a little bit bigger of a market,
but not everyone has a smartwatch and the app might not work with all watches that exist.
Additionally, not all watches will have the same set of sensors,
so we might have to get a little bit creative.
Lastly, building an app will have what I think will be
the largest market because it's something that most people
already have and they'd be able to download and use our app immediately.
How do these industry trends compare with the ones that you found?