Identifying a target user is important,
because it makes it very clear who you're building the product for.
Oftentimes, a problem will best be solved in different ways for different types of users.
Identifying a target user creates focus,
and lets you zoom in on solving the needs of that specific target user.
Remember, if you were building and designing a calculator for a student in grade school,
it would look very different than if you were building a calculator for a scientist.
These users have very different needs,
and very different goals that your product would need to help them accomplish.
Additionally, they also have different purchasing power.
You want to keep your target user in mind,
when you're building a product,
because it will help you to answer a lot of questions
about what your product is, and what it should do.
Your target user is who you are building your product for,
and in order to define your target user,
you will want to identify users with
shared characteristics who are likely interested in your product.
To do this, you'll need to look at a variety of data like market research.
You also can perform interviews,
or conduct surveys and run focus groups.
If you already have customers,
you can look at existing customer data,
and there's lots more.
Once you have this data,
you'll want to look at user characteristics for trends in the following types of things.
Demographics, for example, how old is your user and where do they live?
Motivations, what gets them excited?
Goals, what are they trying to accomplish?
Frustrations, where are they running into current problems and challenges?
Once you've identified trends across these characteristics for your users,
you can create user personas to represent them.
A user persona is a fictional person that you create who might use your product.
As you're developing the product,
you'll refer back to your personas,
in order to stress test and challenge some of your ideas.
For example, does this decision solve Sam's frustration,
and would Sam be able to afford this product?
Let's walk through some of the elements that make up a persona.
You'll want to start by creating a name for your persona.
Personally, I like to use alliteration,
and have the last name describing an attribute of the user like Sam Student.
Another example would be Dan Driver.
It's a nice touch to include a photo,
or illustration of what this user might look like,
as well as a quote with a key insight about this user.
In this case, the quote I'm using is,
"I miss going on my daily morning run."
Keep in mind that it can be really really powerful to
incorporate real quotes from users that you've talked to during user research.
You'll also want to include a description of that user.
This will paint a little bit more of a story about who they are.
It doesn't have to be super in depth,
but you'll want to keep the details focused on things that are relevant to your product.
For example, Sam is just starting her first job out of school,
and lives with two other roommates.
She loves being outside and is a big runner,
but after adjusting to having a new schedule,
she has found it challenging to make time to exercise on a regular basis.
You'll also include frustrations,
or challenges that the user is facing.
In this case, Sam's new schedule makes prioritizing exercise difficult,
and she also feels intimidated to get back into going into the gym.
Then, you'll also want to outline the goals that the user has,
which your product should also help them achieve.
In this example, Sam's goals are to exercise more consistently,
and to be able to complete an upcoming marathon.
Lastly, you'll want to include a few things that motivate the user.
These can be helpful things to consider when designing your product.
In Sam's case, she's motivated by
being able to see her progress and improvement over time,
and she's also motivated by being able to share progress with friends and family,
in order to get support from them.
That's a quick intro to target users,
and how to create user personas.
Now, you should give it a try.