Now, I'm going to walk you through
three personas for potential users that we could target.
John is our first target user.
He is 37 years old and has been increasingly focused on work over the last few years.
As a result, he hasn't been as active and he's put on some extra weight.
For the new year, he made a resolution to lose 20 pounds during the year.
John's frustrations are that work is stressful and keeps him busy.
Another challenge that he's running into is the activities that he finds
relaxing don't necessarily help with his health goals.
For example, video games and eating out.
John's goals are to lose 20 pounds during the year to more
consistently exercise and to find activities that promote good health.
So I'm going to go ahead and summarize John's persona with a quote that,
"My new year's resolution is to lose 20 pounds."
Sally is our second target user.
She is 27 and really enjoys running.
It's one of the few things that really helps her to disconnect.
She's run a few shorter races and recently completed a half marathon.
She is really interested in a full marathon but
wants to train to make sure that she can complete it without injury.
Sally's frustrations are that she wants to make
sure that she can finish a marathon successfully.
She is also a little bit worried about getting injured during the race.
So her goals are really to just complete
a marathon and to avoid getting injured while running.
I'm going to summarize Sally's persona with a quote,
"I want to run my first marathon."
Chris is our third and final target user.
Chris is 32 and has been running competitively for the last 10 years.
Recently Chris feels like things is stalled out and he is not seeing improvements.
Chris' time has remained about the same.
Chris' major frustration is not seeing an improvement in terms of speed,
and the goal that Chris has is to beat his personal best record.
So I'm going to summarize this persona with that quote,
"I want to be my best race time."
So those are the three personas that I created for our target users.
How do they compare to the ones that you created?
Specifically look at the frustrations that I identified and the goals as well.
Were they the same or different and the ones that you identified for your target users?